nzta.govt.nz 2019-12-16

# About this site | NZ Transport Agency

## Copyright

Unless otherwise stated, the information available on or through this website is protected by copyright and subject to the copyright laws of New Zealand. Such information may be reproduced for personal use without permission, as long as you attribute the work to the NZ Transport Agency, and abide by the licence terms under the [Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International licence(external link)](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/ "Link to Creative Commons website. ")

The permission to reproduce copyright protected material does not extend to any material on this site such as logos, emblems, trademarks, photography and imagery, and material identified as being the copyright of a third party. This includes material on websites you access via links from this site. To get permission to reproduce such material, contact the copyright holders concerned.

For permission to reproduce information on this website for any purpose other than personal use, contact the Information Team, NZ Transport Agency, Private Bag 6995, Wellington 6141, New Zealand, or email [informationteam@nzta.govt.nz](mailto:informationteam@nzta.govt.nz "Contact the Information team")

## Disclaimer

  1. The information available on or through this website is intended to provide general information to the public and all reasonable measures have been taken to ensure the quality and accuracy of that information. However, the NZ Transport Agency: 
    * may change, delete, add to or otherwise amend information contained on this website without notice
    * is not responsible for the content of other websites linked to or referenced from this website. (The NZ Transport Agency neither endorses the information, content, presentation or accuracy of such other websites, nor makes any warranty, express or implied, regarding these other websites).
  2. The contents of this website should not be construed as legal advice and, before acting on any information, you should take specific advice from qualified professional people.
  3. Reference to any specific commercial product, process or service, whether by trade name, trademark, manufacture or otherwise, does not constitute an endorsement or recommendation by the NZ Transport Agency.
  4. This site may also contain the advice, opinions and statements of various information providers. The NZ Transport Agency does not represent or endorse the accuracy or reliability of any advice, opinion, statement or other information provided by any information provider, any user of this site or any other person or entity. Reliance upon any such advice, opinion, statement or other information, shall be at the user's own risk.
  5. The NZ Transport Agency does not accept any responsibility or liability whatsoever, whether in contract, tort, equity or otherwise, for any action taken as a result of reading, or reliance placed on the NZ Transport Agency because of having read, any part, or all, of the information in this website or for any error, inadequacy, deficiency, flaw in or omission from the information provided in this site.
  6. Each page on this website must be read in conjunction with this disclaimer and any other disclaimer that forms part of the page or website.

## [](https://www.nzta.govt.nz/about-us/about-this-site/website-terms-of-use/)Privacy

You may browse and access the vast majority of information contained in this website without providing any personal information.

We have software to track which pages are visited, to help us identify the most popular areas of our website. The information is aggregated and we can't identify individual visitors.

Where you voluntarily provide personal information (for example, through email feedback or by completing a form), we’ll use that information only for the purpose for which it was given.

When you subscribe to one of our project update alerts or newsletters, we collect your name and email address. Once subscribed, your details will be added to a mailing list that is used to distribute e-newsletters.

The NZ Transport Agency sometimes uses Campaign Monitor, a dedicated e-newsletter communication tool to easily manage and distribute project news. Campaign Monitor is based in Australia and may use servers based in the United States of America and Europe, and therefore your information may be disclosed or used in such countries. Campaign Monitor will use your information in accordance with its [Privacy Policy.(external link)](https://www.campaignmonitor.com/policies/ "Campaign Monitor: Terms of use")

The Transport Agency monitors the effectiveness of these newsletters using analytical tools offered by Campaign Monitor that collect the following information:

  * Unique opens – The number and email addresses of subscribers that have opened the email
  * Email client usage – which email account (Gmail, Outlook, Hotmail) was used to open the email
  * Regions – Where this email has been opened
  * Bounced – The number of emails that weren’t successful due to an inactive address, DNS failure, or if the recipient’s mailbox was full
  * Not opened – The number and email addresses of subscribers that didn’t open the email
  * Shares – The number of times the newsletter has been shared via email, Facebook or Twitter by subscriber
  * Most popular links – The most clicks on any links directing to other websites or information not contained in the email.

There is no ability to collect information beyond this, or to track the recipient outside of a specific e-newsletter. Once the recipient has closed the newsletter, no further information can be collected.

The NZ Transport Agency holds a variety of information. When dealing with information, the NZ Transport Agency complies with the relevant information legislation, such as the Official Information Act 1982 and the Privacy Act 1993. Where the information is part of a public register, there are specific laws that require the NZ Transport Agency to grant access to certain parts of that information.

You have the right to request access to and correction of that information.

 **Note:  **change of address information is used to update registers that legislation says must be publicly available. Submissions are publicly available too.

If you have any concerns about personal information that we hold, please write to: 

Privacy Officer  
NZ Transport Agency   
Private Bag 6995   
Wellington 6141 

Alternatively you can send an email to [privacy@nzta.govt.nz](mailto:privacy@nzta.govt.nz "Contact NZTA Privacy team")

### Call recording privacy statement

The Transport Agency handles thousands of calls every day on a varied range of topics that include driver licensing, road tolling, motor vehicle registration, and the State highway network.  Call recording is an important activity that helps us to ensure that our customer service meets your expectations and identify service improvements.

### Vehicle screening and traffic analysis

The Transport Agency is implementing vehicle screening cameras at some Commercial Vehicle Safety Centre (CVSC) locations to assist with the enforcement of weight restrictions for heavy vehicles.  If you are in a heavy vehicle and you drive past one of these cameras details of your vehicle will be collected to help determine whether your vehicle meets relevant weight restrictions.  You may be required to stop at the CVSC if the initial screening indicates your vehicle may not meet weight restrictions.  

If you are not in a heavy vehicle and you drive past one of these cameras, the registration plate number of your vehicle will be captured and retained in secure system logs held by the Transport Agency for the purposes of system fault analysis. Access to system logs is restricted to a small number of authorised Transport Agency personnel only and will only be accessed and used for the purposes of analysing faults occurring in the vehicle screening system.  The registration plate number of your vehicle won’t be used to access any personal information held about you by the Transport Agency.  Anonymised information about your vehicle also may be collected and retained for statistical traffic analysis by the Transport Agency.  Your image won’t be captured, you won’t be identified, and no information that can be linked to you will be collected or held. 

### Driver has passed away

To assist the Transport Agency with keeping the national driver licence register up-to-date, the Registrar-General of Births, Deaths and Marriages may notify us when a driver has passed away.

[More about cancelling a driver licence and the driver licence register](https://www.nzta.govt.nz/driver-licences/renewing-replacing-and-updating/licence-holder-has-passed-away/ "Licence holder has passed away")

### Use of your driver licence photo 

The photo captured for your driver licence under Part 3 of the Land Transport (Driver Licensing) Rule 1999 may also be used by the Department of Internal Affairs, Department of Corrections, Ministry of Justice, Ministry of Business, Innovation and Employment (Immigration), New Zealand Customs Service, and the New Zealand Police for the purposes of identity verification and law enforcement under section 200 of the Land Transport Act, or for one of the purposes outlined in Part 10A of the Privacy Act. Your photo may therefore be disclosed to one of these agencies, for one of these purposes.

## Transparency

Our Transparency Statement summarises how the NZ Transport Agency complies with the State Services Commission’s Model Standards on Information Gathering and Public Trust. It describes the environment we operate in and how we gather, use and share information.

## Accessibility

###  **Access keys on this website**

Access keys help people navigate websites using a keyboard rather than a mouse. Most pages on the NZ Transport Agency website use the access keys recommended for New Zealand government websites.

The exact procedure for activating access keys depends on your operating system and browser.

In most browsers, hold down the Alt key or Apple key while typing the access key, then press Enter. For Firefox use Alt+Shift plus the access key.

Access key| Takes you to...  
---|---  
  
h

| 

Home  
  
m

| 

Menu  
  
0

| 

List of access keys  
  
2

| 

Skip to content  
  
3

| 

Skip to top  
  
### Skip links

This site uses a ‘skip to main content’ link which allows screenreader users to skip past navigation links to the main content for the page. You can also do this by using the access key ‘[’.

### PDFs

We've published some documents on this site in PDF format. If your browser doesn't open the PDFs for you, you might need  to install a PDF reader such as Adobe Reader. To get the free Adobe Reader go to the [Adobe website(external link)](https://get.adobe.com/reader/ "Adobe: Download the Adobe Acrobat Reader").

The free Adobe Reader enables you to view, navigate, and browse PDF files, either inside a web browser or in a stand-alone application.
